let's look at the solution to our cache
incoherence quiz we had three caches and
three cores a location that starts at
zero and then each core reads increments
and then writes to that memory location
so the question is what's the final
value we write here the correct behavior
would be four cores zero to do this and
then it replaces this from its cache so
that core 1 reads a 1 here increments
that writes a 2 and then core 2 reads
that increments and writes a 3 so this 3
here is a possible answer if core 0 here
happens to replace this block that
contains a from its cash before core 1
tries to read it and then core 1
replaces before core to reads it and so
on in that case we get actually a 3 here
which is the correct answer so let's see
now if we can get to well if core 0 does
a replacement so the memory location
after this actually contains a 1 then
core 1 does this but doesn't replace the
block from the cache then core to will
still see a 1 it will not see what core
1 produced because core one keeps it in
its own cache so core to here reads 1
increments it and then core 2 ends up
writing a 2 so this is a possible answer
and then we can get a 1 here by
basically core 0 delaying the
replacement and then core 1 can fetch a
0 as well put a 1 there but not replace
until later and that means that when
core 2 reads this it gets a 0 and then
puts a 1 here so this is also possible
it is not possible for core 2 to write a
0 because whatever it reads it will
increment and write
so for Core 2 to produce a 0 here it
would need to read minus 1 note that
each of these cores is still behaving as
a correct uniprocessor so 0 is not
possible
similarly for is not possible because
for 4 to be produced here we need to
read a tree and there is just no way
that to increase
from zero can produce a three here and
similarly more than four is not possible
so the correct answers here are 1 2 & 3
are possible at this point